hey folks David Tao with barbend.com and
today we have a recap of day three of
the 2023 Noble CrossFit Games
[Music]
today also marks the beginning of
individual and team competitions there
were three events so we already have a
leaderboard starting to shake out and
some big surprises including notable
names not performing as well or as high
on the leaderboard as we might have
expected after a few events so we've got
all that and more stick around
[Music]
I do want to give a quick note please if
you like this content you want to stay
up to date on all things CrossFit Games
and really all things strength including
stuff from the world of powerlifting
weightlifting strongman bodybuilding and
more make sure you subscribe to Barb and
on YouTube yeah this Channel on YouTube
the thing you're watching right now go
ahead and make sure you subscribe
alright let's start with the men and
we're going to start with event one this
was the mountain bike or the event
simply called ride
[Music]
competitors had to do as many laps on a
course as possible in 40 minutes with a
Trek mountain bike and not a huge
surprise as to who won this event on the
men's side yonakowski who is a European
Behemoth in the world of CrossFit we've
heard his name at the top for around a
decade now does very well on endurance
events notably Jeffrey Adler of Canada
who's always really in the mix for the
top 10 sometimes the top five especially
as we saw back in the 2020 pandemic
CrossFit Games he finished second in
this event one notable name for the men
on the ride event that's going to come
up again and again throughout this
broadcast well that's Justin Medeiros
the two-time reigning fittest man on
Earth didn't exactly perform Super well
in the event finishing 29th now we've
seen ultimate winners of the CrossFit
Games come out of the gate a little bit
slow especially on endurance events
these longer endurance events we've seen
the game start with these sorts of rides
or runs or rocks or swims in the past
sometimes you have like a triathlon
event so it's not necessarily indicative
of his Fitness level but then again
Justin madiros tends to do well on
longer monostructural events after all
you don't get to be the two-time
defending champ without some significant
capacity there so that kind of raised
our eyebrows and got us thinking wonder
if something's up with the defending
champ just something to keep in mind and
we'll reference that again later in this
broadcast all right let's talk about
ride on the women's Side Oh Canada it
was Canada and Canada in first position
and second position young Emma Lawson
gets her first ever CrossFit Games event
win with a win on ride and Emily Rolfe
also of Canada takes the number two spot
let's talk about event two the pig
chipper we had a pyramid of pig flips
chest of our pull-ups toaster bar and
wall ball shots so you go up and then
you go back down with the wall ball
shots in the middle Roman krenikov
Podium finisher from last year actually
competing for the United United States
this year because he cannot compete as a
Russian athlete due to International
sanctions well he takes the event win
here this is right up Roman's alley
classic CrossFit chipper style multiple
movements a mix of weights and gymnastic
movements and you really got to keep the
pace consistent throughout not surprised
to see him take the top spot here it
really goes to show chronikov is in fine
form he's a name that had come up as a
potential not only Podium Contender but
potential fittest man on Earth so we're
going to be paying close attention to
Roman throughout the weekend on the
women's side the winner of the pig
shipper is a very familiar name
multi-time CrossFit Games Podium
finisher Lara Horvath now here's the
thing about Laura she's always had a few
gaps that some thought kept her from
being the fittest woman on earth
handstand push-ups notable among them
but let's be honest the main thing
keeping Laura Horvath from being the
fittest woman on earth over the last few
years has been Tia clear to me who's not
competing this year so Lara Horvath
really showcasing her Fitness really
showing that if you have that classic
CrossFit mix of weights and gymnastic
movements and you got to push the pace
from start to finish yeah she's the
woman to beat this weekend so event
number three was the inverted medley and
traditionally this is something very
high skilled very gymnastic that we've
seen actually on the second or last day
of competition for individuals at the
CrossFit games but the programmers
decided to put it first this year and
this thing had everything handstand
walks pirouettes freestanding handstand
push-ups pullovers I mean you're upside
down basically the entire time but
basically super super high skill
gymnastic movements it just goes to show
the high level proficiency all of these
athletes have on high skill gymnastic
movements because they're basically all
expected to be able to perform this
workout to completion and even just a
few years ago some of these movements
would have been out of the question even
at the CrossFit Games it's a good
illustration of the sports ever solution
let's talk about how the men did on the
men's side Cole grishaber of CrossFit
Lee's Summit takes the event when second
on the inverted medley oh there's Justin
Medeiros good to see him he hadn't
finished in the top 20 in either of the
first two events here is a two-time
defending champion at actually gaining
some ground and making some points on
day one oh and by the way on event
number two the pig chipper just the
madiro's finished way back of the pack
in 37th so the two-time defending
Champion clearly has some ground to make
up and had fans Spectators even
announcers wondering is he injured
something seems to be off with Justin
Maderos on the inverted medley obviously
he's making up some points and showing
that he's great upside down but heading
into day two at least day two of the
individual competition some big
questions about Justin maderos's Fitness
and form coming into this competition in
first place on the women's side a name
that's very familiar to longtime fans of
the sport perennial top 10 competitor
Danielle Brandon now she finished in
21st and 21st on the first two events so
definitely a good sign to see Danielle
make up some ground in a crew some
points here now let's talk about overall
standings on day one of individual
competition just three events plenty of
points left in play over the course of
the next three days but in first place
overall on the men's side we've got
Roman krenikov he's a Podium finisher
from last year he's representing the
United States this year he is someone
who folks thought could make a move not
only at the podium again but at the
overall title of fittest man on Earth
and he's come out of the gates really
strong 21 points Behind karenikov still
in very much in moving position is Jay
Crouch of Australia the games veteran
has performed consistently on the first
three events so far and he's placed
himself in really spitting distance of
Roman depending on how the next few
events shake out 21 points is not a lot
in the grand scheme of the CrossFit
Games it's also worth noting that Jay
Crouch finished in the top 10 on all
three events on day one
it's a good way to start the games
Spencer panchic of the United States a
member of the panchic family CrossFit
Games Dynasty sits in third with 225
points he's clearly in very good form
this year by the way his older brother
Scott who burst onto the scene over a
decade ago it's his first year competing
as a masters athlete some other big
names and Veterans to note in the top 10
on the men's side Patrick Belen or Brent
fakowski and bjorkvan Carl Goodmanson
all sitting in top 10 position let's
talk about the women's side standings
after day one Alexis raptis the 24 year
old American sits in first place overall
with very consistent finishes across the
first three events actually Alexis has
been the model of consistency with top 5
finishes on the first three events
that's pretty indicative of a high level
of Fitness skill and strength we're
gonna have our eyes on her all weekend
has the American already established
herself as the person to beat this
weekend Emily Rolfe of Canada sits in
second place and Ariel lowen of the
United States sits in third place Emma
Lawson of Canada sits in fourth and
nipping at their heels is a name well
we've heard this name for almost 15
years at the CrossFit games that's Annie
Thor's Daughter of Iceland remember last
year she actually took the year and
competed as a team representing her gym
CrossFit Reykjavik this year she's is
back as an individual looking to improve
or at least match her Podium performance
from 2021 when she came back the year
after giving childbirth actually not
even a year after giving birth came back
and made the podium can she come back
and do it again this year she's sitting
in fifth after one day of competition
and he's an athlete we're used to seeing
move a little later in competitions and
make those big moves on Saturdays and
Sundays so I'm really excited to see it
and we're cheering for the original
daughter as they like to say Iceland
Annie Annie thorosotter sitting in fifth
place showing that even though she's
been competing in the sport at the
highest level since 2009 she's still a
mega relevant name now let's talk about
Laura Horvath for a second she's sitting
in seventh place but she performed very
well in the first two events not so well
in the third event but is that really a
bad thing for Lara Horvath we know one
of her weaknesses has always been when
things get inverted handstand push-up
handstand walks it's just not the thing
she's best at now the fact that the
inverted medley is over the fact that
that's the event most likely that had
the highest concentration of upside down
movements all weekend could spell good
things for Laura because she's still in
seventh place overall it didn't knock
her back out of the top 10 after day one
seventh place is still very much moving
position so expect the multi-time podium
finisher and the person some thought was
positioned to inherit Tia claritumi's
Crown well expect her to make some moves
and I wouldn't be surprised if she
cracked the top five after day two but
there's a lot of Fitness to be had and a
lot of events to be seen we are
recapping the age group and adaptive
divisions from the 2023 Noble CrossFit
Games there were a lot of Divisions and
I want to be clear we're not going to be
able to list the podium for each and
every one of them because we're talking
nearly 30 divisions and well we don't
have a 40 minute video to do that in
full results are going to be on
barbend.com so make sure to check those
out at the link below oh all right let's
address an elephant in the room and
that's the fact that the video coverage
of the age group and adaptive divisions
at this year's CrossFit Games was a
little disappointing it got to the point
where CrossFit CEO Dawn fall actually
had to address the fact that well there
wasn't a ton of great video coverage at
least not compared to the individual and
teams divisions it's worth noting there
are a lot of age groups and there are a
number of adaptive divisions a lot of
these events run simultaneously across
different venues and frankly CrossFit
just doesn't have the capacity according
to CEO Dawn fall to film all of these in
Dynamic angles multi-camera setups Etc
there are 18 age group divisions and six
adaptive divisions that's 24 divisions
that's a lot of Podium finishers and I'm
not even that good at math here's the
good news we have coverage of all of
these not necessarily in this video but
all of them in detail on barbend.com so
while we didn't add a lot of camera
capacity to this year's coverage when it
comes to these divisions we added a ton
of writing capacity we have been
covering these like the Dickens do
people still say that probably not if
nothing else please check out that
coverage at the link below or at
barbin.com again there we've got full
coverage of every age group Division and
every adaptive division we think it's
important and we were really really
enjoying ourselves as we watched those
divisions we're able to highlight some
of those stories even highlight which
athletes out of those divisions had to
withdraw for whatever reason the
individual started off with three events
today the team started off with just two
the first event they started off with
was 2222 Redux where teams had to
accumulate 175 overhead squats while
doing a bunch of other stuff in the
middle we can go ahead and list that
work out on the screen so you can get an
idea of it event number two was a little
similar to individual event number one
ride relay teams had two bikes that had
to complete a number of laps in an hour
let's talk about standings for the teams
after day one of competition Crossfit
Invictus that's a name I've been hearing
a lot over the last decade sits in the
first place overall CrossFit Oslo navy
blue sits in second and Crossfit East
Nashville proven prvn that is the
training program and general fitness
ecosystem run by Tia claritumi and Shane
Orr the married couple you've heard of
them they sit in third place overall so
there you have it the end of Visual and
Team Action from Thursday the first day
for those two divisions at the 2023
Noble CrossFit Games the last year the
CrossFit Games will be in Madison as far
as we know a lot of exciting things
going on including a defending champ on
the men's side who seems to have fallen
way back in the pack and has a lot of
room to cover and on the women's side we
have a wide open field it's really
anyone's ball game this year with so few
top 10 competitors from last year back
and Performing and competing this year
so we will have a new fittest woman on
earth it seems like we may have a new
fittest man on Earth but we're gonna
have to wait until Sunday for those
final results until then I'm David Tao
with barbend.com make sure to tune in to
barbin.com for event coverage and all of
the action all weekend long thanks for
tuning in
[Music]
thank you